# Clara Nelson

607-342-7906 | claran@alumni.cmu.edu | claranelson.github.io

## SUMMARY

Senior software engineer with product focused mindset. Experienced in weighing trade-offs across engineering and business considerations. Proven ability to provide quality experiences for users and developers independently and in teams. Academic training in data structures and algorithms using C from Carnegie Mellon University.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ordergroove August 2021 - present

**Senior Software Engineer**, Merchant Growth Team (Full stack, Front-end focus)

December 2022 - present

- Subject matter expert on Shopify integration
  - Designed and presented technical architecture training for Shopify and cart offers
  - Led inter-team coordination to upgrade to Shopify App Embeds and trained team members
- Proposed, prototyped, and evaluated improvements to dashboards that are fully code-customizable by merchants and serve millions of subscribers
  - Led technical refinement and prototyping of plugin-based option to update merchant-edited code
  - Created flow in merchant portal for merchants to upgrade to code editor from legacy template
- Made tech and product suggestions for team projects, such as new design system and multi-currency support
- Advocated for accessibility improvements, including scoping and resolving compliance with WCAG Level AA
- Resolved or routed urgent merchant and internal tickets requiring engineer input

**Software Engineer**, Merchant Growth Team (Front-end focus)

July 2022 - December 2022

- Implemented re-branding of merchant portal serving DTC merchants ranging from SMB to Enterprise
- Created productized cart offers for Shopify based on learnings from Partnerships Team proof of concept

**Software Engineer**, Partnerships Team (Back-end focus)

August 2021 - July 2022

- Adopted Shopify's latest webhooks and APIs to improve Ordergroove's webhook integration
- Created proof of concept for cart offers on Shopify

# ARUP

July 2019 - August 2021

## **Full Stack Developer**

April 2021- August 2021

- Independently maintained and added features to Python automation handling time-sensitive documents
- Scoped, estimated, and completed new Python automation projects for internal clients

#### **Advanced Technology and Research Graduate Analyst**

July 2019 - March 2021

- Created relational database and interfaced with MongoDB to create Power BI dashboards
- Ensured the correctness of a weather program while improving performance by 5000x

## **EDUCATION**

## Carnegie Mellon University Master of Science in Civil Engineering

May 2019

Focus Area: Advanced Infrastructure Systems — Intelligent Buildings

GPA: 4.0

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms (course 15-122)

#### Carnegie Mellon University Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering

May 2018

GPA: 3.92, Minor: Philosophy

## **SKILLS**

Languages: Javascript, Python, Go, SQL, C

Frameworks/Tools: React, Redux, Node.js, Liquid, LESS, MongoDB, Django, Jest, Selenium, WAVE, Axe Devtools